防患於未然
Brace the wind.
陛下 光之王已完全兌現承諾
The Lord of Light has made good on his promise, my king.
他的火焰消融了積雪
His fires have melted the snows away.
前路暢通
The way ahead is clear.
進軍臨冬城
We ride for Winterfell.
你定能馬到功成
And you will take it.
主讓我看到波頓之旗在烈焰中燃燒
The Lord has shown me Bolton banners burning.
你會得到你合法的王位
You will receive what is yours by right.
陛下
Your Grace.
準備整隊進軍
Prepare to form up.
陛下
Your Grace.
講
Tell me.
大批士兵 在黎明前叛逃
The men, many deserted before dawn.
逃了多少
How many?
將近半數
Nearly half.
所有傭兵也把戰馬都騎走了
All the sellswords with all the horses.
陛下
Your Grace.
有話直說 還有什麼能糟過叛逃
Speak up. Can't be worse than mutiny.
放她下來
Cut her down.
陛下
Your Grace.
剛剛梅麗珊卓夫人也逃離軍營了
The Lady Melisandre was just seen riding out of camp.
召集剩餘人馬列隊
Get the men into marching formation.
進軍臨冬城
On to Winterfell.
只見他舉高雙手
He raised his hands
所有死人就立刻站起身來
and they all stood up at once.
數以萬計 簡直是這世上最強大的軍隊
Tens of thousands of them. The biggest army in the world.
你打算怎麼對付他們
So what are you gonna do?
只能希望他們不會爬城牆
I'm gonna hope they don't learn how to climb the Wall.
但那些龍晶...
But the dragonglass...
沒人拿得回來了
No one's ever getting that back now.
再說作用也不大
It wouldn't have mattered anyway.
除非我們有一大堆
Not unless we had a mountain of it.
可你殺了一個異鬼啊
But you killed a white walker.
用長爪劍
With Longclaw.
他們擊碎鋼斧 就像擊碎玻璃一般
I saw them shatter steel axes like they were glass.
-但那長爪劍   -是瓦雷利亞鋼
- But Longclaw... - Is Valyrian steel.
七大國內現存幾把瓦雷利亞鋼劍
How many Valyrian steel swords are left in the Seven Kingdoms?
屈指可數
Not enough.
我是史上第一任
The first Lord Commander in history
為挽救野人性命
to sacrifice the lives of sworn brothers
而犧牲了守夜人兄弟的總司令
to save the lives of wildlings.
跟黑城堡裏最招恨的人交友
How's it feel to be friends
感覺如何
with the most hated man in Castle Black?
從我第一天來此 你就是我朋友
You were friends with me when I first came here.
我那時可沒機會贏得什麼選舉
And I wasn't winning any elections back then.
敬我倆一杯
Here's to us, then.
隨他們挖苦去吧
Long may they sneer.
怎麼了
What?
我想求你件事
I wanted to ask you something.
只能向你求助
To ask something of you.
把我 吉莉和孩子派去舊鎮
Send me, Gilly, and the baby to Oldtown
這樣我就有機會成為學士
so I can become a maester.
那才是我的志向所在 而不是當戰士
That's what I'm meant to be. Not this.
山姆 你得留下
I need you here, Sam.
如果你走了 誰還能為我提供可靠建議
If you leave, who's left to give me advice I trust?
不是還有艾德嗎
Well, there's Edd.
我當上學士的話 會對你更有幫助
I'd be more use to you as a maester.
因為伊蒙學士不在了 我會比任何人都更有用
More use to everyone now that Maester Aemon is gone.
學城有世上最大的圖書館
The Citadel has the world's greatest library.
我會學到很多歷史 謀略 醫術
I'll learn about history, strategy, healing.
還有其他知識
And other things,
能在異鬼來襲時派得上用場
things that will help when-- when they come.
要是吉莉還得留下來 她會沒命的
If Gilly stays here, then she'll die.
被她起名叫山姆的那孩子也會沒命
And the baby that she named after me will die.
最後為了保護他們 我也會搭上性命
And I'll end up dying, too, trying to protect them.
如此一來 我臨死前看到的最後一幕
Which means that the last thing that I'll see in this world
將是他們被我辜負之後失落的眼神
will be the look in her eyes when I fail them.
我寧願直面萬千異鬼 也不願如此
And I'd rather see a thousand white walkers than see that.
謝謝你
Thank you.
到了學城 他們還是會逼你立誓戒色的
You know that the Citadel will make you swear off women, too.
有種他們試試看
Oh, they'll bloody try.
-山姆  -怎麼了
- Sam. - What?
山姆
Sam.
你剛被人打得半死 你是怎麼...
You had just been beaten half to death. How did you--
我很小心的
Oh, very carefully.
很高興世界末日還能給某人帶來點好處
I'm glad the end of the world's working out well for someone.
我會回來的
I'll come back.
祝你早日歸來
To your return.
祝我早日歸來
To my return.
嘿 這邊
Aye, this way.
小姐
My lady!
史坦尼斯
Stannis.
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩率領全部人馬殺來了
Stannis Baratheon is coming. His whole army.
你怎麼知道是史坦尼斯
How do you know it's Stannis?
他們舉著烈焰紅心旗
They're carrying his flaming heart banners.
我在黑水河之役見過 絕對忘不了的
From the Blackwater. I'll never forget it.
在這兒挖戰壕
Trench here.
距城牆三百碼的地方再挖一道
Another one 300 yards from the castle wall.
動作要快
Hurry them along.
-對了 克魯  -在 陛下
- Right, Curlew. - Yes, sir.
在那兩條斜坡間挖一道
Dig between those two rises.
-分散開  -我和你一起
- Spread out. - I'm with you.
-弓箭手!  -散開!
- Archers! - Spread out!
即刻派一隊人徵收糧草
And send out a foraging party immediately.
日出之時攻城
Siege begins at sunrise.
陛下 無法攻城了
There's not going to be a siege, Your Grace.
我們沒法兒贏的
We've got no chance!
別殺我 求你了
No, please, please.
居然有女人為波頓出戰
Bolton has women fighting for him?
我並不是為波頓家而戰
I don't fight for the Boltons.
我是塔斯的布蕾妮
I'm Brienne of Tarth.
曾任藍禮·拜拉席恩的御林鐵衛
I was Kingsguard to Renly Baratheon.
他被跟你同樣面孔的黑影殺死時 我在場
I was there when he was murdered by a shadow with your face.
是你用血魔法殺了他嗎
You murdered him with blood magic?
是我
I did.
以拜拉席恩家族
In the name of Renly of House Baratheon,
藍禮一世之名
First of His Name,
以安達爾人和先民之合法國王
rightful King of the Andals and the First Men,
七大王國統治者和全境守護之名
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm,
我 塔斯的布蕾妮 判你死刑
I, Brienne of Tarth, sentence you to die.
有什麼遺言嗎
Do you have any last words?
盡你的職責 動手吧
Go on, do your duty.
看來任務完成了
Looks like we're done here.
我投降!
I surrender! I surrender!
我接受你的投降
And I accept your surrender.
我們回去吧
Let's head back.
我妻子肯定寂寞了
My wife must be lonely.
夫人
My lady.
我來護送你歸寢
I've come to escort you back to your chamber.
請跟她走吧
Go with her, please.
我知道拉姆斯的為人
I know what Ramsay is.
知道他會怎麼對付我
I know what he'll do to me.
如果我注定要死
If I'm going to die,
讓我死得有尊嚴些吧
let it happen while there's still some of me left.
死
Die?
誰說你要死了
Who said anything about dying?
你不能死
You can't die.
你父親是北境守護
Your father was Warden of the North.
拉姆斯需要你
Ramsay needs you.
不過他可不需要你的全部
Though I suppose he doesn't need all of you.
只需要能為他生育子嗣的部分
Just the parts he'll use to make his heir,
等你為他生養了一兩個男孩之後 就沒用了
until you've given him a boy or two and he's finished using them.
他就會找些駭人聽聞的招數對付你
Then he's got incredible plans for those parts.
那我們要等他回來
So, shall we wait for him to come back
還是現在就開始呢
or should we begin now?
你讓我決定
You're leaving it to me?
那好
Good.
現在開始吧
Let's begin.
臭佬... 住手!
Reek... stop!
住手!
Stop!
打開城門!
Open the gate!
他回來了
He's coming back.
看來我有事要做了
I can see I have my work cut out for me.
你倆滾出去
You two, out.
你在我名單上排第一 知道嗎
You were the first person on my list, you know.
你可記得殺了西利歐·佛瑞爾嗎
For killing Syrio Forel. Remember him?
記不清了
Probably not.
還有幾個我要殺的人
I've gotten a few of the others.
千面神讓我忘卻很多
The Many-Faced God stole a few more from me.
幸虧他還把你留給我
But I'm glad he left me you.
知道我是誰嗎
Do you know who I am?
我聽不清
I can't hear you.
你知道我是誰
You know who I am.
我是艾莉亞·史塔克
I'm Arya Stark.
你知道你是誰嗎
Do you know who you are?
你是無名之輩
You're no one.
無足輕重
You're nothing.
女孩取走一條性命
A girl has taken a life.
不該取走的性命
The wrong life.
我說對了
I was right about her.
確實
You were.
你還沒準備好
You're not ready.
完全沒有
Not at all.
那人的命不該由你來取
That man's life was not yours to take.
女孩從千面神那裏偷竊
A girl stole from the Many-Faced God.
如今她生有所欠
Now a debt is owed.
唯有死亡才能償還
Only death can pay for life.
不要啊!
No! No!
不要 你... 你別死!
No, you... don't die! Don't die!
你為何哭泣
Why are you crying?
他是我朋友
He was my friend.
他不是 你不懂他說的話嗎
No, he wasn't. Didn't you listen to him?
他是無名之輩
He was no one.
可如果你是...
But if you're...
那這是誰
who's this?
無名之輩而已
No one at all.
女孩從大廳取走人面之前
Just as a girl should have
也應該是無名之輩
been before she took a face from the hall.
人面為心無牽掛之人準備
The faces are for no one.
你依然心有牽掛
You are still someone.
對心有牽掛的人
And to someone,
人面堪比毒藥
the faces are as good as poison.
我看不見了
I can't see.
怎麼了
What's happening?
怎麼回事
What's happening?!
-祝你歸途平安  -謝謝
- I wish you a safe journey home. - Thank you.
原諒我 孩子
Forgive me, child.
願你福星高照
I wish you all the happiness in the world.
說不定我會去探望你
Maybe I'll come visit you sometime.
說不定是我探望你呢
Maybe I'll come visit you.
早點來吧
Don't wait too long.
家裏有個貴族千金等我去娶呢
Got a noblewoman to marry back home.
你想娶個賢良淑女
You want a good girl,
卻需要個風騷浪女
but you need the bad pussy.
就等你了 爵士
Whenever you're ready, my lord.
這次別跟丟了
Try not to lose it this time.
我再也不讓它離身
I'll never take it off again.
我知道你不想離開多恩
I know you didn't want to leave Dorne,
但我很高興你要回家了
but I'm glad you're coming home.
你母親對你萬分牽掛
Your mother's desperate to see you.
我也高興崔斯丹與我們同行
I'm glad Trystane is coming with us.
他是個好小伙
He seems like a nice boy.
你很幸運
You're lucky.
媒妁婚姻很少能...
Arranged marriages are rarely so...
如此美滿
so well arranged.
你說母親會喜歡他嗎
Do you think Mother will like him?
只要看到你開心 她一定會喜歡的
If she sees you're happy, I'm sure she will.
你真的這麼想嗎
You really believe that?
除了自己的子女
Have you ever known your mother to like anyone
你見過母親喜歡過別人嗎
aside from her children?
她喜歡你
She likes you.
我可不確定
I'm not so sure about that.
聽著...
Listen...
有件事我想告訴你
there's something I wanted to tell you.
也許我早該告訴你
Something I should have told you long ago.
所以...
So...
你現在已見過世面
now that you've seen more of the world,
也該明白世事多變
you've learned how complicated things can be,
人心險惡
people can be.
蘭尼斯特家與馬泰爾家曾是世仇
The Lannisters and the Martells have hated each other for years,
可你卻愛上崔斯丹
but you've fallen in love with Trystane.
真有點意外 我是說 該有多巧
It was an accident, really. I mean, what were the chances?
你剛好愛上了
You happen to fall in love with the man
指定要嫁的人
you were assigned to marry?
其實...
My point is...
我們無法選擇所愛的人
we don't choose whom we love.
只是...
It just, well...
我們情難自禁
it's beyond our control.
-是不是聽起來很傻  -不 才不是
- I sound like an idiot. - No, you don't.
我只是想說... 我想說
What I'm trying to say... what I'm trying
卻沒能說出口的... 我知道你要說什麼
and failing to say... I know what you're trying to say.
不 你不知道
No, I'm afraid you don't.
我知道
I do.
I know.
你和母親的事
About you and Mother.
一直隱約知道
I think a part of me always knew.
我真的很高興
And I'm glad.
為你是我父親而高興
I'm glad that you're my father.
彌塞菈
Myrcella?
彌賽菈
Myrcella? Myrcella?
你們愛她 對吧
You love her, don't you?
怎能不愛呢
How could you not?
當然你倆實在是希望渺茫
Of course it's hopeless for the both of you.
一個競技場的傭兵 一個失寵的騎士
A sellsword from the fighting pits, a disgraced knight.
你們的身份都配不上女王
Neither one of you is fit consort for a queen.
我們卻總是會愛上不該愛的女人
But we always want the wrong woman.
他總是這麼聒噪嗎
Does he always talk so much?
安達爾人喬拉
Jorah the Andal.
灰蟲子
Torgo Nudho.
他不該在這兒
He should not be here.
是 可他確實在
No, but he is.
女王已下令將他逐出城去
Our queen ordered him exiled from city.
若不是因為他 女王已經死了
Our queen would be dead if not for him.
是真的 我差點也死掉 若不是因為這位...
小壯士
侏儒
應該是這個詞
抱歉
我的瓦雷語鼻音有些重
有些澀
生澀 謝謝
Punela. Thank you.
很抱歉
I am sorry.
我沒能在場為女王而戰
Sorry I not there to fight for our queen.
你可真錯過了一場好戲
You missed a good scrap.
那些都不重要了
None of that matters now.
我們在這兒戲謔得越久
The longer we sit here bantering,
丹妮莉絲在野外待的時間越長
The longer Daenerys is out there in the wilderness.
他說的沒錯 龍朝北飛了
He's right. The dragon headed north.
要找到她 我們就得往北走
If we're going to find her, that's where we'll have to go.
我們
We?
你是個蘭尼斯特
You're a Lannister.
女王一心要把你們家族趕下王座
The queen intends to remove your family from power.
而我一心助她實現夙願
And I intend to help her do it.
你到這兒才多久呢
You've been here for how many days now?
我已為她戰鬥多年
I've fought for her for years.
自她年幼時起
Since she was little more than a child.
-你背叛了她 -說話留神
- You betrayed her. - Careful now.
她放逐了你 兩次 我記得
And she exiled you. Twice, I believe.
第二次拜你所賜
The second time thanks to you.
莫爾蒙 別把你的錯怪到我頭上
Don't blame me for your crimes, Mormont.
他說得對 女王放逐了喬拉
He's right. Our queen exiled Jorah.
他說的也沒錯 喬拉救了女王
And he's right. Jorah saved her life.
也許她的看法有變
Perhaps she feels differently about him now.
也許沒有 只有去問她才能知道
Perhaps not. The only way we'll know is if we ask her.
好吧 讓他加入我們吧
Fine, fine. I suppose he can join us.
只要他保證不趁我睡覺時殺了我
Just as long as he promises not to kill me in my sleep.
如果我要殺你 你可得時刻提防
If I ever kill you, your eyes will be wide open.
等等 我們憑什麼要帶上你
Forgive me, but why would we bring you?
什麼意思
Pardon me?
你在野外捕過獵嗎
Have you ever tracked animals in the wilderness?
沒 但我有別的本事
Not precisely, but I have other skills that would be useful.
你很會打嗎
Can you fight?
我以前打過
I have fought.
不敢自稱偉大的戰士
I don't claim to be a great warrior.
你騎術如何
Are you good on a horse?
還好
Middling.
你也就是會耍嘴皮
So mainly you talk.
還會喝酒 我至今還活著
And drink. I've survived so far.
我尊重你 但這次遠征你幫不上忙
Which I respect, but you would not help us on this expedition.
不過你可以在彌林幫助我們
You would help us here in Meereen, though.
我們沒人能夠治理一座城市
None of us have experience governing a city
除了他
except for him.
你想向女王證明你的價值
You want to prove your value to the queen?
就在彌林這裏證明吧
Prove it right here in Meereen.
他是個外國侏儒 不懂本地語
He's a foreign dwarf that barely speaks the language.
彌林人怎麼會聽他的
Why would the Meereenese listen to him?
他們不會聽他的
They wouldn't.
但會聽灰蟲子的
They will listen to Grey Worm.
我要跟你們去
I'll come with you.
我會找到女王
I'll find our queen.
-你身體太弱不便走動  -我能走
- You are not strong enough to go anywhere. - I am.
他能 他是我見過的最有種的閹人
He is. He's the toughest man with no balls I ever met.
但你還是不能去
But you still can't go.
彌林人相信你
The people believe in you.
他們知道你代表女王
They know you speak for the queen.
是的
It's true.
只有無垢者能維護彌林穩定
Only the Unsullied can keep the peace in Meereen.
如果你走了 這個城市會發生內亂
If you leave, half this city will consume the other half.
還有彌桑黛
And Missandei.
女王最信任的人是彌桑黛
Our queen trusts no one more than Missandei.
而不是我
Certainly not me.
女王的閨中密友
The queen's closest confidante,
無垢者的指揮官
the commander of the Unsullied,
疤臉的外國侏儒
and a foreign dwarf with a scarred face.
祝你們好運 我的朋友
Good fortune, my friends.
彌林古老而輝煌
Meereen is ancient and glorious.
千萬別把它毀了
Try not to ruin her.
好像就剩我倆了 安達爾人喬拉
Looks like it's you and me, Jorah the Andal.
去找幾匹好馬
Let's find some good horses.
我們有太多話要聊
We have so much to talk about.
你好 老朋友
Hello, old friend.
我以為我們相處得很愉快 你卻棄我於不顧
I thought we were so happy together until you abandoned me.
你是怎麼找到我的 這問題大概也沒意義了
I suppose there's no point asking how you found me.
鳥鳴於西 鳥鳴於東
The birds sing in the west, the birds sing in the east,
只要你會側耳傾聽
if one knows how to listen.
它們說 你已另有用武之地
They tell me you've already found favor
輔佐龍母
with the Mother of Dragons.
她的確沒處死我
Well, she didn't execute me,
這算是個好開始
so that's a promising start.
現在英雄們都離城去找她了
Now the heroes are off to find her
我卻被困在這裏
and I'm stuck here
還要安撫這座城市 避免內亂
trying to placate a city on the brink of civil war.
有什麼像樣的建議嗎
Any advice for an old comrade?
情報最關鍵
Information is the key.
要清楚敵人的力量和戰略
You need to learn your enemy's strengths and strategies.
要分清哪些是真盟友 哪些不是
You need to learn which of your friends are not your friends.
如果我認識一個消息靈通的人士該多好
If only I knew someone with a vast network of spies.
但願如此
If only.
一個宏偉古城 掣肘於暴力 腐敗和謊言
A grand old city choking on violence, corruption, and deceit.
誰會有能耐去駕馭
Who could possibly have any experience
這麼個巨大又笨拙的野獸
managing such a massive, ungainly beast?
我確實懷念過你
I did miss you.
我知道
Oh, I know.
我們必須得回去
We have to go home.
可憐的小傢伙
Oh, my poor, sweet thing.
是不是很疼
Does it hurt?
我們必須得回去
We have to go home.
卓耿
Drogon.
能帶我回彌林嗎
Can you take me back to Meereen?
你帶我飛了多遠？
How far did you carry me?
卓耿 我們得回去
Drogon, we need to return.
我的子民需要我
My people need me.
對了 沒吃的了
Well, there's no food.
再怎麼說 晚上你能搞點吃得來吧
At the very least, you could hunt us some supper.
認罪
Confess.
我有罪
I have sinned.
我承認
I see that now.
我許久以來怎能如此盲目
How can I have been so blind for so long?
我想重獲清白
I want to be clean again.
望能免除罪責
I want absolution.
我夢到老嫗高舉聖燈
The Crone came to me with her lamp raised high.
在聖光照耀下...
And by its holy light--
想認罪嗎
You wish to make a confession?
若我認罪 可否重獲自由
Once I've confessed, will I be free?
那要看太后所犯何罪了
Your Grace will be dealt with according to her sins.
聖母仁慈為懷
The Mother have mercy, then.
我承認 我跟其他男人有婚外姦情
I lay with a man outside the bonds of marriage. I confess.
他叫什麼
Name him.
藍賽爾·蘭尼斯特
Lancel Lannister.
你的堂弟 先王的侍從
Your cousin and the king's squire.
-我那時寂寞無助  -你是有夫之婦
- I was lonely and afraid. - You had a husband.
可我丈夫一門心思在外尋花問柳...
A husband off whoring every chance he--
你不能拿他的罪行為自己開脫
His sins do not pardon your own.
願諸神寬恕我
May the gods forgive me.
還有別人嗎
Other men?
沒了
No.
真沒了
No others?
沒了
No.
欺騙諸神 罪不可恕
Speaking falsehoods before the gods is a great crime.
你可明白
You understand this?
明白
I do.
傳言說你的三個孩子
There are those that say your children
並非勞勃國王親骨肉
were not fathered by King Robert,
傳言說他們是通姦亂倫所生的雜種
that they are bastards born of incest and adultery.
謊言
A lie.
定是史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩編造的謊言
A lie from the lips of Stannis Baratheon.
他圖謀篡奪王位 卻被其侄捷足先登
He wants the throne, but his brother's children stand in his way.
所以故意造謠說孩子非勞勃親骨肉
So he claims they are not his brother's.
卑鄙無恥
That filth.
這種傳言絕不可信
There is not one shred of truth to it.
我否認
I deny it.
很好
Good.
但這些指控所涉罪名嚴重
But these are terrible charges.
全國上下必須知道真相
And the realm must know the truth of them.
若太后的供詞屬實
If Your Grace has given honest testimony,
審判定能還你清白
your trial will prove your innocence.
審判 我已認罪
Trial? I have confessed.
只認了一項罪
To a single sin.
其餘罪名你都否認了
Others you have denied.
審判自能辨別孰是孰非
Your trial will separate the truths from the falsehoods.
謹遵總主教的睿智決斷
I bow to the wisdom of Your High Holiness.
可我能否懇求聖母
But if I might beg
對我略施仁慈呢
for just one drop of the Mother's mercy.
我已許久未見我兒子...
I haven't seen my son--
早已記不清有多久了
I don't know how long it's been.
請允許我見見他
I need to see him, please.
你已邁出皈依正道的第一步
You have taken the first step on the path back to righteousness.
有鑒於此
In light of this,
你可以返回紅堡
I will permit you to return to the Red Keep.
謝謝你
Thank you.
謝謝總主教
聖母仁慈
The Mother is merciful.
應該謝她
It is her you should thank.
那是 那是
I will. I will.
我發誓 會日夜向她禱告
I swear it, day and night.
很好
Good.
我可以走了嗎
Am I free to go?
等贖罪執行後
After your atonement.
贖罪
My atonement?
一個罪人來到你們面前
A sinner comes before you.
蘭尼斯特家族的瑟曦
Cersei of House Lannister.
國王托曼陛下的生母
Mother to His Grace King Tommen.
先王勞勃陛下的遺孀
Widow of His Grace King Robert.
她犯下欺騙與通姦之罪
She has committed the acts of falsehood and fornication.
她已認罪並祈求諸神寬恕
She has confessed her sins and begged for forgiveness.
為證明她有心悔過
To demonstrate her repentance,
她將拋開所有尊嚴 詭詐
she will cast aside all pride, all artifice,
把諸神創造她時的本貌
and present herself as the gods made her
展現給全城的善男信女
to you, the good people of the city.
她滿懷謙卑而來
She comes before you with a solemn heart,
褪去所有的隱私
shorn of secrets,
在諸神和世人面前赤裸…
naked before the eyes of gods and men...
踏上贖罪之路
to make her walk of atonement.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
可恥
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
-騷逼!  -無恥
- Cunt! - Shame.
-罪人!  -婊子!
- Sinner! - Whore!
-無恥!  -婊子!
- Shame. - Whore!
無恥
Shame.
-婊子!  -無恥
- Whore! Whore! - Shame.
無恥
Shame.
婊子! 罪人!
Whore! Sinner!
-無恥  -賤貨! 操你弟的!
- Shame. - Bitch! Brother fucker!
-婊子!  -無恥
- Whore! - Shame.
-滾吧!  -無恥
- Fuck off! - Shame.
無恥
Shame.
-向皇室的奶頭致敬  -你個賤貨!
- All hail the royal tits. - You're a bitch!
無恥
Shame.
-干她!  -婊子!
- Get her! - Whore!
-賤貨!  -混蛋!
- Bitch! - Fucker!
-混蛋!  -你個賤貨!
- Fucker! - You bitch!
-無恥  -騷逼!
- Shame. - Cunt!
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
-操你弟的!  -賤貨!
- Brother fucker! - Bitch!
我玩過的屌只有太后的一半多
I've had half as many cocks as the queen.
-賤貨!  -無恥
- Bitch! - Shame.
-無恥  -罪人! 婊子! 蕩婦!
- Shame. - Sinner! Whore! Slut!
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
-婊子!  -婊子
- Whore! - Whore, whore.
我是蘭尼斯特 給我吹簫啊!
I'm a Lannister. Suck me off!
-給我吹簫啊 你個賤貨!  -退後!
- Suck me off, you bitch! - Back!
-婊子!  -無恥
- Whore! - Shame.
無恥
Shame.
妓女
Whore!
婊子 淫婦 娼妓
Whore! Whore! Whore!
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
-賤貨! 賤貨!  -無恥
- Bitch! Bitch! - Shame.
操你弟的!
Brother fucker!
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
-婊子!  -操你弟的!
- Whore! - Brother fucker!
-婊子!  -無恥
- Whore! - Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
-無恥  -混蛋!
- Shame. - Fucker!
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
無恥 無恥
Shame. Shame.
無恥
Shame.
陛下
Your Grace.
你回來了就好
It's good to have you back.
來
Come.
我們扶你進去
We'll take you inside.
我要看看你腳上的傷
I need to have a look at those feet.
我可否有幸介紹一位御林鐵衛新成員
May I have the honor of presenting the newest member of the Kingsguard?
為了陛下 他已立下靜默聖誓
If it please Your Grace, he has taken a holy vow of silence.
他發誓不再開口說話
He has sworn that he will not speak
直到陛下所有的仇敵被剷除
until all His Grace's enemies are dead
所有的惡徒被驅逐
and evil has been driven from the realm.
當初是誰救了你 史坦尼斯
Who came to your aid? Stannis.
如今他需要你
Now he needs you.
我們兵力太弱 難以扭轉戰局
We don't have enough men to make any difference.
野人加入則能改變形勢
The wildlings will make a difference.
野人絕不會為史坦尼斯而戰
The wildlings will never fight for Stannis.
-我早就跟他說過  -你救過他們的命啊
- I told him before. - You saved their bloody lives.
他們若想在七大國境內生存
If they're gonna live in the Seven Kingdoms,
靠長城保命 就得為這鬼地方而戰
safe behind our Wall, they ought to fight for the damn place.
-這場戰爭不屬於他們  -打開城門!
- It's not their fight. - Open the gates!
史坦尼斯呢
Stannis?
希琳 小公主呢
Shireen? The princess?
總司令
Lord Commander.
有個你帶回來的野人
It's one of the wildlings you brought back.
他說認識你叔叔班揚
Says he knows your Uncle Benjen.
說他還活著
Says he's still alive.
你確定他說的是班揚
Are you sure he's talking about Benjen?
據他說是首席游騎兵
Said he was First Ranger.
還說知道去哪兒能找到他
Said he knows where to find him.
那人說上次滿月時在艱難屯見過你叔叔
Man says he saw your uncle at Hardhome at the last full moon.
-說不定是撒謊  -有這可能
- Could be lying. - Could be.
有辦法確定真假
There are ways to find out.
-他人呢  -在那兒
- Where is he? - Over there.
叛徒
為了守夜人
For the Watch.
奧利...
Olly...
為了守夜人
For the Watch.
~第五季終~
FIX鐵王座的世界組傾情奉獻